export const vit_2_mesl_part_2 = [
    {
        choices: ["vacuum pressure", "gage pressure", "zero pressure", "absolute temperature"],
        correctAnswer: "absolute temperature",
        question: "The measure of the ability to transfer heat to other bodies based on reference tempreature where a body has given up all the thermal energy it possibly can;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["independent of cut off ratio", "no answer", "increased", "decreased"],
        correctAnswer: "independent of cut off ratio",
        question: "The mean effective pressure of a diesel cycle having  fixed compression ratio will increase if cut off ratio is ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Lenz law", "Torricelli&amp;amp;#39;s theorem", "Archimedes principle", "Bernoulli&amp;amp;#39;s principle"],
        correctAnswer: "Torricelli&amp;amp;#39;s theorem",
        question: "The velocity of a liquid with discharges under a head is equal to the velocity of the body which falls in the same head.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["perpetuity", "annuity due", "ordinary annuity", "deferred annuity"],
        correctAnswer: "deferred annuity",
        question: "An annuity whereby payment is postponed for a certain period of time",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["pressure only", "volume only", "temperature only", "no heat transfer"],
        correctAnswer: "no heat transfer",
        question: "An ideal gas is contained in a rigid container. There is no work of a rotating shaft associated with the container. Any heat transfer is a function of:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Pitot tube", "Manometer tube", "Draft tube", "Venturi tube"],
        correctAnswer: "Pitot tube",
        question: "It is an instrument for measuring with accuracy the flow rate of fluids in pipes;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["liquid filled", "no answer", "Fahrenheit or centigrade scale", "ordinary thermometer with wet gauze on bulb"],
        correctAnswer: "ordinary thermometer with wet gauze on bulb",
        question: "A wet bulb thermometer is a ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["capillary action", "vacuum", "atmospheric pressure", "surface tension"],
        correctAnswer: "atmospheric pressure",
        question: "A pump suction line is hitting water 10 feet. What force makes water flow into the pump?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["impulsive forces", "sensitive forces", "resistive forces", "reactive forces"],
        correctAnswer: "impulsive forces",
        question: "Forces that act for very short periods of time are referred as;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["effective interest", "simple interest", "nominal interest", "compounded interest"],
        correctAnswer: "effective interest",
        question: "Actual interest earned by a given principal",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["energy", "power", "momentum", "force"],
        correctAnswer: "power",
        question: "THe moment of of a moving object is the product of its mass (m) and velocity (v). Newton&amp;amp;#39;s second law of motion says that the rate of change of momentum with respect to the time is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["silicon dioxide", "sulfur dioxide", "hydrogen dioxide", "nitrogen dioxide"],
        correctAnswer: "nitrogen dioxide",
        question: "The main cause of air pollution as a result of burning fuel is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Darcy equation", "no answer", "Euler equation", "Bernoulli equation"],
        correctAnswer: "Darcy equation",
        question: "The total pressure drop for a turbulent flow pipe can be calculated from",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["payback period", "return on investment", "price earning ratio", "recievable turnover"],
        correctAnswer: "payback period",
        question: "The length of time usually in years for the cumulative net annual profit to equal the initial investment is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["fixed assets", "land and buildings", "current assets", "total assets"],
        correctAnswer: "current assets",
        question: "Liquid assets such as cash and other assets that can be converted quickly to cash, such as accounts receivables and merchandise are called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["molybdenum", "tungsten", "stainless steel", "all of the above"],
        correctAnswer: "stainless steel",
        question: "An alloy metal is a/an",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["tangibles", "investment", "intangibles", "capital"],
        correctAnswer: "tangibles",
        question: "Things that can be quantitatively measured or valued such as item of costs and physical assets are:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Stirling", "Otto", "Brayton", "Rankine"],
        correctAnswer: "Rankine",
        question: "A steam power cycle is modeled by the ideal cycle known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["rectangle", "rhombus", "polygon", "rhomboid"],
        correctAnswer: "rhombus",
        question: "An equialateral parallelogram is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["collateral bond", "debenture", "mortgage bond", "lien bond"],
        correctAnswer: "lien bond",
        question: "A bond whereby the security behind it are the equipment of the issuing corporation.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["high pressure bypassing", "low pressure bypassing", "short cycling", "hot gas bypassing"],
        correctAnswer: "hot gas bypassing",
        question: "A method of reducing capacity without reducing compressor speed.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["epicycloid", "cardiod", "hypocycloid", "cycloid"],
        correctAnswer: "epicycloid",
        question: "Locus of points on a slide which roll along a fixed line:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["tangent", "sine", "straight line", "square root"],
        correctAnswer: "sine",
        question: "Tidal motion is normally related to which mathematical function?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["clearance volume", "cut off volume", "maximum volume", "engine displacement"],
        correctAnswer: "engine displacement",
        question: "Volume displaced by each piston moving from bottom dead center to top dead center multiplied by a number of cylinders.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["melting point", "dew point", "saturation point", "boiling point"],
        correctAnswer: "dew point",
        question: "Temperature at which air begin to liquefy",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["scavenging", "blowby", "purging", "supercharging"],
        correctAnswer: "scavenging",
        question: "Removal of spent gases from an internal combustion engine cylinder and replacement by a fresh charge of air",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["at least 18 years of age", "a citizen of the Philippines", "a certified plant mechanic", "a holder of BSME degree"],
        correctAnswer: "a certified plant mechanic",
        question: "Which is not qualification for an applicant for ME board examination?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["energy", "work", "heat", "entropy"],
        correctAnswer: "heat",
        question: "What is the area of the diagram from the relation of temperature and entropy plane.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["specific gravity of battery acid", "air velocity", "flue gas temperature", "brine concentration"],
        correctAnswer: "air velocity",
        question: "A pitot tube is used to measure",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["all of the above", "silencers", "ear mufflers", "head muffler"],
        correctAnswer: "silencers",
        question: "Noise of exhaust gases of diesel engines or a gasoline engine can be reduced by",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["5.0 kg", "10.5 kg", "7.5 kg", "2.25 kg"],
        correctAnswer: "10.5 kg",
        question: "How much water must be evaporated from the 18 kg of 20% salt solution to produce a 50% solution.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["quality of steam", "boiler pressure", "quantity of steam generated", "type of fuel"],
        correctAnswer: "boiler pressure",
        question: "Total solid impurities of feedwater for a boiler depend upon",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["elevation", "bearing", "direction", "depression"],
        correctAnswer: "bearing",
        question: "The angle of the line of sight on the stationary object referred from the standard directions",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["112.5 liters/37.5 liters", "212 liters/53.7 liters", "211 liters/3.5 liters", "121.5 liters/53.7 liters"],
        correctAnswer: "112.5 liters/37.5 liters",
        question: "How much of a 40% solution of alcohol and how much of an 80% solution should be mixed to give 150 liters of a 50% solution?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["mortgage bond", "lion bond", "collateral bond", "debenture bond"],
        correctAnswer: "collateral bond",
        question: "Type of bond in which the security behind are teh assets of a well known subsidiary",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["isentropic stagnation state", "isothermal stagnation state", "isobaric stagnation state", "isometric stagnation state"],
        correctAnswer: "isentropic stagnation state",
        question: "State of flowing fluid would attain if it were brought to rest reversibly in a steady-state steady flow device involving no heat transfer and no work transfer.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["length", "outside diameter", "thread length and pitch", "inside diameter"],
        correctAnswer: "inside diameter",
        question: "The nominal diameter of a pipe is the",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["knocking", "surging", "drooping", "turbulence"],
        correctAnswer: "turbulence",
        question: "As applied to diesel engine operation, it is the disturbance of the sprayed fuel oil and the air within the combustion chamber or cylinder.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["flame impingement", "unequal firing", "furnace overload", "temperature failure"],
        correctAnswer: "flame impingement",
        question: "Unequal distribution of combustion in the furnace is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["carbon dioxide", "sulfur dioxide", "nitrogen", "carbon monoxide"],
        correctAnswer: "carbon monoxide",
        question: "INcomplete combustion product in flue gases is ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Society of Automotive engineers", "Society of Automatic engines", "Society of Automotive emollients", "Society of Automotive engines"],
        correctAnswer: "Society of Automotive engineers",
        question: "SAE represents",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["harmonic progression", "geometric progression", "no answer", "arithmetic progression"],
        correctAnswer: "geometric progression",
        question: "A series of numbers having the common ratio:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["22", "21", "23", "20"],
        correctAnswer: "23",
        question: "Find the last term of the series of numbers 2,5,8,... to the 8th term.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Alemberts principle", "Newton&amp;amp;#39;s second law of motion", "Newton&amp;amp;#39;s first law of motion", "Torrecelli&amp;amp;#39;s theorem"],
        correctAnswer: "Newton&amp;amp;#39;s second law of motion",
        question: "The rate of change of momentum is directly proportional to the applied force producing the change and takes place in the direction of this force is referred as;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["decreased", "zero", "increased", "the same"],
        correctAnswer: "decreased",
        question: "The boiling point of water in an open container at sea level is 100 degree Celsius. If the pressure on the open container is decreased, such as going up to the top of a mountain, the boiling point will be:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["efficiency test", "temperature test", "conductivity test", "hydrostatic test"],
        correctAnswer: "hydrostatic test",
        question: "A test being used for boilers to detect leaks and to check water tightness after certain repairs.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["50 hp", "150 hp", "400 hp", "300 hp"],
        correctAnswer: "400 hp",
        question: "The maximum horsepower rating of mechanical works or plant that can be tended or operated by a certified plant mechanic is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["heat rise", "volume", "pressure", "vacuum"],
        correctAnswer: "heat rise",
        question: "Viscosity of a liquid decreases with",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["air duct", "nozzle", "diffuser", "weir"],
        correctAnswer: "diffuser",
        question: "When a fluid flows through a passage of varying cross section, its velocity varies from a point to point along the passage. If the velocity decreases, the passage is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["pump", "water jacket", "radiator", "thermostat"],
        correctAnswer: "radiator",
        question: "It serves as a heat exchanger of the cooling system of the cylinder in which the water is cooled by the forced flow of the atmospheric air around the pipes or tubes carrying the water.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["absorption", "conduction", "radiation", "convection"],
        correctAnswer: "radiation",
        question: "Transmission of heat from a hot body to a cold body by electromagnetic waves",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["a point function", "a path funciton", "exact differential", "discountinuous"],
        correctAnswer: "a point function",
        question: "Mathematically a thermodynamic property is which of the following?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["puring", "turbocharging", "blowby", "scavenging"],
        correctAnswer: "blowby",
        question: "Leaking of a fluid between a cylinder and its piston during operation.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["40", "80", "60", "70"],
        correctAnswer: "80",
        question: "How many liters of a 60% solution of a sulfuric acid be added to 40 liters of a 30% solution to obtain a 50% solution of acid?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["acid indicator slide chart", "all of the above", "alkalinity indicator slide chart", "percent of hydrogen ion content"],
        correctAnswer: "all of the above",
        question: "What is PH",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["throttle avlve", "reducing valve", "gate valve", "globe valve"],
        correctAnswer: "gate valve",
        question: "Type of valve which should be used only wide open or fully closed",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["has high modulus of electricity", "it is ductile", "it is plastic", "it is elastic"],
        correctAnswer: "it is elastic",
        question: "A certain specimen is subjected to a load. When the load is removed, the strain disappears. Which of the following can be deduced about this material?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Atomic number", "Reynold&amp;amp;#39;s number", "Moody&amp;amp;#39;s number", "Avogadro&amp;amp;#39;s number"],
        correctAnswer: "Reynold&amp;amp;#39;s number",
        question: "A measure of ratio of inertia to viscous forces in burning fuel",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["probability", "progression", "combination", "permutation"],
        correctAnswer: "probability",
        question: "A number of occurrences of a certain event per total number of occurences",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["rectangle", "rhomboid", "rhombus", "polygon"],
        correctAnswer: "rhombus",
        question: "A parallelogram is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["gasoline engine", "Diesel engine", "Otto engine", "gas engine"],
        correctAnswer: "Diesel engine",
        question: "Compression ignition engine is also known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["PME", "CPM", "MPE", "RME"],
        correctAnswer: "PME",
        question: "Minimum grade of a mechanical engineer required in the design and preparation of plans of 280 kW diesel power plant.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["fuel heating value", "moisture content", "torque strength", "flow characteristics"],
        correctAnswer: "flow characteristics",
        question: "Saybolt Universal charts refer to",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["compression ratio", "fuel used", "torque", "speed"],
        correctAnswer: "compression ratio",
        question: "Air standard efficiency of a diesel engine depends on",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["rate of return", "break even point", "none of the above", "law of diminishing return"],
        correctAnswer: "break even point",
        question: "The percentage of capacity of operation of a manufacturing plant at which income will just cover expenses.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["mechanically", "unit injector", "hydraulically", "pneumatically"],
        correctAnswer: "unit injector",
        question: "A diesel engine which uses a continuous pressure pump, the fuel is introduced into the combustion chamber of the cylinder.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Bernoulli&amp;amp;#39;s principle", "D&amp;amp;#39;Alemberts principle", "Torrecelli&amp;amp;#39;s theorem", "Archimedes principle"],
        correctAnswer: "Archimedes principle",
        question: "If a solid body floats, or is submerged in a liquid, the liquid exerts an up thrust on the body equal to the gravitational force on the liquid displaced by the body;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["no answer", "call in pay", "down time pay", "lost time pay"],
        correctAnswer: "down time pay",
        question: "A term used to describe payment of an employee for time spent on the property of the employee though not actually working at the job.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["specific density", "specific gravity", "relative humidity", "relative density"],
        correctAnswer: "specific gravity",
        question: "Ratio of the density of substance to the density of some standard substance",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["there is no zero on this scale", "freezing point of water", "boiling point of water", "there is no zero on this scale"],
        correctAnswer: "freezing point of water",
        question: "Zero degrees centigrade",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["permutation", "combination", "progression", "probability"],
        correctAnswer: "permutation",
        question: "An ordered arrangement of a group of things or an arrangement of objects in definite order",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["rate of investment", "interest", "rate of return", "surplus"],
        correctAnswer: "rate of investment",
        question: "The peso amount as earned from an investment or project.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["aerator", "dehydrator", "humidifier", "trap"],
        correctAnswer: "dehydrator",
        question: "A device used to keep moisture from passing through the system is called:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["increased", "remains the same", "decreased", "double"],
        correctAnswer: "decreased",
        question: "A pendelum has a certain frequrency of oscillation in London. Assuming that temperature remains the same, the frequency of oscillation of the pendulum it is measured on the equator will:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["throttling process", "adiabatic process", "isometric process", "isothermal process"],
        correctAnswer: "adiabatic process",
        question: "If mass of steam is expanded in a cylinder in such a manner that no energy is added or lost as heat",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["work", "compressive power", "rotation", "stress"],
        correctAnswer: "rotation",
        question: "Torque is a force which tends to produce ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["corrosion", "exposure stress", "no answer", "caustic embrittlement"],
        correctAnswer: "caustic embrittlement",
        question: "The weakening of boiler steel as the result of inner cyrstalline cracks is known as",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["coefficient of linear expansion", "coefficient of superficial expansion", "coefficient of cubic expansion", "coefficient of volume expansion"],
        correctAnswer: "coefficient of linear expansion",
        question: "The amount by which a unit length of a material expands when the temperature is raised one degree is referred as;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["thread pitch", "outside diameter", "length", "inside diameter"],
        correctAnswer: "inside diameter",
        question: "Pipe size is measured by the",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["32.75", "40.00", "36.75", "30.00"],
        correctAnswer: "36.75",
        question: "A hoist with a 100 hp engine is capable of lifting a 10, 000 pounds load, a height of 20 feet in 10 seconds. The efficiency of this machine in % is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["moment of inertia", "center of attraction", "center of gravity", "center of inertia"],
        correctAnswer: "center of gravity",
        question: "The point through which the resultant of the distributed gravity force passes regardless of the orientation of the body in space is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["stagnation point", "emanation point", "detonation point", "chocking point"],
        correctAnswer: "stagnation point",
        question: "A point in a field of flow about a body where the fluid particles have zero velocity with respect to the body.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["cold zero", "perfect zero", "absolute zero", "double zero"],
        correctAnswer: "absolute zero",
        question: "As heat is removed from the substance, it gets colder. When no more heat can be removed and the temperature cannot be lwoered any further, we have reached:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["Pitot tube", "Weir tube", "Piezometer tube", "Venturi tube"],
        correctAnswer: "Pitot tube",
        question: "It is a device for measuring the velocity of moving fluids or of the velocity of bodies moving through fluids;",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["diffuser efficiency", "weir flow efficiency", "nozzle efficiency", "isentropic flow efficiency"],
        correctAnswer: "diffuser efficiency",
        question: "Ratio of the outlet stagnation pressure to the inlet stagnation pressure is referred as:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["uses dual blowers to purge cylinders", "no answer", "air traveling in one direction", "air reversing direction in a cylinder"],
        correctAnswer: "air traveling in one direction",
        question: "What takes place in a uniflow scavenging?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["polygon", "pyramid", "rhomboid", "circle"],
        correctAnswer: "rhomboid",
        question: "A parallelogram with oblique triangles and only the opposite&amp;amp;#39;s sides are equal.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["6930", "3069", "3960", "9630"],
        correctAnswer: "3069",
        question: "Find the sum of the first 10 terms in the series of numbers 3, 6, 12, 24 ....",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["before the end of compression stroke", "at the beginning of compression stroke", "after fuel cut off", "at the end of compression stroke"],
        correctAnswer: "before the end of compression stroke",
        question: "In a diesel engine, fuel is injected",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["165 m", "180 m", "160 m", "173 m"],
        correctAnswer: "180 m",
        question: "A rubber ball was dropped from a height of 36 m and each time it strikes the ground, it rebounds to a hieght of 2/3 of the distance from which it fell. Find the total distance traveled by the ball before it comes to rest.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["convection", "absorption", "radiation", "conduction"],
        correctAnswer: "convection",
        question: "A process of heat transfer due to motion of matter caused by a change in density.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["atomization", "excess air", "rapid oxidation", "slow oxidation"],
        correctAnswer: "rapid oxidation",
        question: "Combustion is",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["too light fuel", "too high fuel pressure", "too much lubricating oil", "too heavy oil"],
        correctAnswer: "too light fuel",
        question: "In a low speed engine, which of the following may cause black smoky exhaust?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["1 min", "4 min", "3 min", "2 min"],
        correctAnswer: "4 min",
        question: "How long a current of 5 amperes pass through a 10 ohms resistor until a charged of 1200 coulombs passes through.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["none of the above", "rocker arm", "valve timing", "tappet clearance"],
        correctAnswer: "tappet clearance",
        question: "Adjustment of valves to open and close at the proper time for smooth and efficient operation of the engine.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["steam engine", "thermocouple", "friction", "burning fuels"],
        correctAnswer: "friction",
        question: "If electrical energy is converted to heat energy by an electric fire, mechanical energy is converted to heat energy by:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["combustion chamber", "evaporator", "regenerator", "heater"],
        correctAnswer: "regenerator",
        question: "Heat exchanger used to provide heat transfer between the exhaust gases and the air prior to its entrance to the combustor",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["over pressure", "in low elevation deserts", "under pressure", "under vacuum"],
        correctAnswer: "under vacuum",
        question: "Water will boil at a lower temperature",
        topic: "NA"
    },
      {
        choices: ["refrigerant", "all of the above", "heat", "non condensable gases"],
        correctAnswer: "non condensable gases",
        question: "To purge air in an air conditioning system means to remove",
        topic: "NA"
    },
]